[
    {
        "question": "What are the different types of real data type in C ?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "float, double",
        "b": "short int, double, long int",
        "c": "float, double, long double",
        "d": "double, long int, float",
        "answer": "float, double, long double"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will you do to treat the constant 3.14 as a long double?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "use 3.14LD",
        "b": "use 3.14L",
        "c": "use 3.14DL",
        "d": "use 3.14LF",
        "answer": "use 3.14L"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the binary eauivalent of 5.375 in normalised form is 0100 0000 1010 1100 0000 0000 0000 0000, what will be the output of the program (on intel machine)?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\n#include<math.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float a=5.375;\r\n    char *p;\r\n    int i;\r\n    p = (char*)&a;\r\n    for(i=0; i<=3; i++)\r\n        printf(\"%02x\\n\", (unsigned char)p[i]);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "40 AC 00 00",
        "b": "04 CA 00 00",
        "c": "00 00 AC 40",
        "d": "00 00 CA 04",
        "answer": "00 00 AC 40"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement will you add in the following program to work it correctly?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    printf(\"%f\\n\", log(36.0));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "#include<conio.h>",
        "b": "#include<math.h>",
        "c": "#include<stdlib.h>",
        "d": "#include<dos.h>",
        "answer": "#include<math.h>"
    },
    {
        "question": "We want to round off x, a float, to an int value, The correct way to do is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "y = (int)(x + 0.5)",
        "b": "y = int(x + 0.5)",
        "c": "y = (int)x + 0.5",
        "d": "y = (int)((int)x + 0.5)",
        "answer": "y = (int)(x + 0.5)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The binary equivalent of 5.375 is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "101.101110111",
        "b": "101.011",
        "c": "101011",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "101.011"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will you do to treat the constant 3.14 as a float?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "use float(3.14f)",
        "b": "use 3.14f",
        "c": "use f(3.14)",
        "d": "use (f)(3.14)",
        "answer": "use 3.14f"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statement obtains the remainder on dividing 5.5 by 1.3 ?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "rem = (5.5 % 1.3)",
        "b": "rem = modf(5.5, 1.3)",
        "c": "rem = fmod(5.5, 1.3)",
        "d": "Error: we can't divide",
        "answer": "rem = fmod(5.5, 1.3)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float a=0.7;\r\n    if(a < 0.7)\r\n        printf(\"C\\n\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"C++\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "C",
        "b": "C++",
        "c": "Compiler error",
        "d": "Non of above",
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float *p;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", sizeof(p));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "2 in 16bit compiler, 4 in 32bit compiler",
        "b": "4 in 16bit compiler, 2 in 32bit compiler",
        "c": "4 in 16bit compiler, 4 in 32bit compiler",
        "d": "2 in 16bit compiler, 2 in 32bit compiler",
        "answer": "2 in 16bit compiler, 4 in 32bit compiler"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float fval=7.29;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", (int)fval);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0",
        "b": "0.0",
        "c": "7.0",
        "d": "7",
        "answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\n#include<math.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    printf(\"%f\\n\", sqrt(36.0));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "6.0",
        "b": "6",
        "c": "6.000000",
        "d": "Error: Prototype sqrt() not found.",
        "answer": "6.000000"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\n#include<math.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", sizeof(3.14f), sizeof(3.14), sizeof(3.14l));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "4, 4, 4",
        "b": "4, 8, 8",
        "c": "4, 8, 10",
        "d": "4, 8, 12",
        "answer": "4, 8, 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float f=43.20;\r\n    printf(\"%e, \", f);\r\n    printf(\"%f, \", f);\r\n    printf(\"%g\", f);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "4.320000e^+01, 43.200001, 43.2",
        "b": "4.3, 43.22, 43.21",
        "c": "4.3e, 43.20f, 43.00",
        "d": "Error",
        "answer": "4.320000e^+01, 43.200001, 43.2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float a=0.7;\r\n    if(a < 0.7f)\r\n        printf(\"C\\n\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"C++\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "C",
        "b": "C++",
        "c": "Compiler error",
        "d": "Non of above",
        "answer": "C++"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\n#include<math.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float n=1.54;\r\n    printf(\"%f, %f\\n\", ceil(n), floor(n));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "2.000000, 1.000000",
        "b": "1.500000, 1.500000",
        "c": "1.550000, 2.000000",
        "d": "1.000000, 2.000000",
        "answer": "2.000000, 1.000000"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float d=2.25;\r\n    printf(\"%e,\", d);\r\n    printf(\"%f,\", d);\r\n    printf(\"%g,\", d);\r\n    printf(\"%lf\", d);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "2.2, 2.50, 2.50, 2.5",
        "b": "2.2e, 2.25f, 2.00, 2.25",
        "c": "2.250000e+000, 2.250000, 2.25, 2.250000",
        "d": "Error",
        "answer": "2.250000e+000, 2.250000, 2.25, 2.250000"
    }
]